ZUHAYR TARIQ

AFOHS Falcon Complex #IH203, Karachi, Pakistan · +923041420123

Zuhayrtariq4@gmail.com

https://zuhayrtariq.github.io/Portfolio/

OBJECTIVE

Seeking career advancement and looking for a role where I can utilize my Full Stack Development skills.

SUMMARY

Highly motivated and dedicated individual with 3+ years of experience in the field of full stack web development. Currently a student at IoBM having majors in Computer Science. Having strong grip on numerous programming languages including JavaScript, PHP and C++. An excellent problem solver, good with finding creative solutions for challenging problems, love to work in a team of developers that are goal oriented and motivated. Currently working on sharpening my skills in React and Node JS.

EDUCATION

AUGUST 2019 - PRESENT

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (BSCS), INSTITUTE OF BUSINESS

MANAGEMENT

Current CGPA: 3.81

FEBRUARY 2022 – JULY 2022

EXCHANGE PROGRAM (BSCS), ISTANBUL AYDIN UNIVERSITY

CGPA: 3.88

JULY 2017 - JULY 2019

HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE, FAZAIA DEGREE COLLEGE FAISAL

Awarded Grade: B

EXPERIENCE

AUGUST 2022 – JANUARY 2023

FULL STACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER, TFM DIGITAL

Worked remotely for TFM Digital. Performing duties of both front end and back end developer.

NOVEMBER 2021 – JANUARY 2022

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY INTERN, LUCKY CEMENT LIMITED

Worked with SAP ABAP. Looked after their databases and helped them with debugging of errors in the system.

PROJECTS

TFM EXPRESS

- Developed a mobile responsive website and integrated booking and payment functionality. Worked with JavaScript, NodeJS, Mailchimp and Stripe API.
- Link: https://tfm.express/

EZ SOLVERS

- Worked in a team of three members and developed EZ Solvers website *Ezsolvers.com*. Worked mostly on the front-end side using technologies that include HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP.
- Link: https://ezsolvers.com/

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Awarded Presidential Merit Scholarship at IoBM for the year 2020-2021
- Awarded Presidential Merit Scholarship at IoBM for the year 2019-2020

ADDITIONAL COURSES

- The Complete Web Developer in 2022: Zero to Mastery by Andrei Neagoie
- The Advanced Concepts (2023 Update) by Andrei Neagoie
- Modern React with Redux [2023 Update] by Stephan Grider
- Node JS: Advanced Concepts by Stephan Grider

AREA OF EXPERTISE

- Front End Web Development
- Back End Web Development
- Responsive Layouts and Design

- Database Management
- Git/Version control

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Node JS

- Express JS
- React JS
- EJS
- Tailwind CSS

- Bootstrap
- MySQL
- PHP
- MongoDB

SKILLS

- Strong Problem-Solving Skills
- Self-Focused
- Goal Oriented

- Critical Thinking
- Self-Awareness